Hey, this week, what is even going on?
It's August. Wasn't this supposed to be
the slow phase of the year? We got so
many super super significant AI releases
in just one week that well, I'll just
have to rush through some of the
stories. So, this video is not an hour
long. We finally got the GPT5 release,
but then also Claude released Opus 4.1
and Gemini released their Deepthink
model. In other words, new and better
flagship models out of the three biggest
players. And then there's so much more
interesting stuff like runway shipping,
a feature that is essentially Photoshop
for video. What the heck? Didn't expect
that. And a music generator that sounds
incredible. You haven't heard anything
like it before. All of that and more in
this week's episode of AI news you can
use. Show where I round up all the AI
releases. We filter for the ones that
are usable now and then show you real
world use cases or testing results. So,
let's begin by following up with the
GPT5 story. I already uploaded a lengthy
video covering the entire release and my
first impressions on it. If you want to
see comparisons between the competing
models on both benchmarks and actual use
cases, then that video is your friend.
You can find it linked in this card.
What we'll be doing here today is
following up with that video on how
other people have been using it and what
the general sentiment around GBD5 is so
far. So let's switch to my screen and
look at some practical ways to use this
new model which is even available on the
free plan now in ways that you might
have not considered yet. Okay. And in
here I want to hit three main points.
First of all the interface because it's
a bit different than they actually
presented. Look in the pro plan I have
three different models to select from.
Then I want to talk about some examples
of its main use case which is
development. I have a really fantastic
practical example here comparing it to
Claude's results on a very big repo that
I'm working on. And then lastly, I want
to give you my take on what models I
will be using for some of my main use
cases day-to-day. Okay, so starting out
with the model selector. In their
presentation, they essentially said that
there's going to be no more model
selection, but this is not entirely
true. If you're on the free plan, which
is most people, then you only get GPT5
and you get this additional option to
think longer. So, also the fact that
you're not going to be able to select
its thinking depth is also not entirely
true. Even on the free plan, you can
always make it think longer, think a bit
harder, which by the way caused a lot of
confusion with some people because in
some cases it's referred to as
reasoning. Here it's referred to as
thinking. The technical term would be
chain of thought. But then in reality,
thinking and reasoning in humans is
different from what the models are
actually doing here. It's sort of just a
term that has been used to express that
it's going to be circling back to its
ideas and reviewing them in multiple
rounds. Either way, there's more options
when you upgrade through the plan. So,
on the plus plan, you're going to have
access to the GPT5 thinking, which just
takes more time to think through the
answer. And then on the pro plan, which
is the $200 plan, you get GPT5 Pro,
which they didn't even talk about. And
actually, I've been using this ever
since release. This model is insane. And
I think a lot of the opinions you hear
online are not based on this one. Like,
just keep this in mind. If you're on
Reddit, on Twitter, heck, even on
YouTube, most people are not on the $200
plan. They're going to be judging this
model with thinking longer, probably
turned off. And then yeah, a lot of the
opinions now are, hey, it's not as
impressive as people think. Well, I
would say two things. First of all,
they're probably not using one of these
options. And secondly, most of those
opinions that I've seen over the past
day come from people who don't do
development at all. That is the biggest
selling point and the biggest upgrade
for power users of this model. And
that's why the two examples I want to
look at now will be development related.
But I really wanted to make this point
because you got to take the opinions of
people on the internet with a grain of
salt. I mean, if I just look at the
video that I uploaded yesterday, the
opinions range all the way from, "Wow,
great examples. Thank you for showing
how it actually performs." All the way
to first 10 minutes are useless. But,
you know, one of them probably comes
from a person who watched the entire
90-minute presentation. So, they have
the basics and they do not need a
summary, which literally is timestamped
as a summary. So, that's the problem
with the internet. But, here we look at
actual examples. So, let's do that.
Let's move into the second part, which
is kind of evaluating its ability to
help developers. In short, holy
guacamole, it's so good. Like, first of
all, I managed to resolve a issue that
no other model before this could solve.
Well, so for a bit of context, I'm
working on this application, which is
essentially like an operating system for
my company. This is just a little
preview, but it has these different
modules and then I can combine multiple
automations and custom tools and
prompts, everything that I have into
operating system for my people to
actually use without them being
developers. And this project has become
quite lengthy over the past weeks.
Matter of fact, it's 27,000 lines of
code. Most of it generated with clot
code, but I'm at the phase where I'm
actually working with proper developers
to harden it and make it solid so I can
use it for myself and then also help
other companies with actually
implementing AI. Now, here's the thing.
I took that entire repo, downloaded the
zip file, and I wanted to harden the
module management, something that I've
really been struggling with inside of
Clot Code over the past days. I tried
Gemini, I tried Claw Opus 4.1, but none
of the results were satisfactory. When I
ran this prompt through GPT5 Pro and
then I gave it the entire application,
it fought for 15 minutes and came up
with a fantastic plan. If you're a
developer and interested in this, you
can kind of pause and have a look at
this. Point being, this is an excellent
and very realistic plan considering
where I'm actually at with the
application. So to compare afterwards, I
went ahead and ran the same prompt
through Claude. Now, one problem there
was it couldn't even take the entire
context of the repo cuz it's so big by
now. So I had to leave out certain
files. it did end up working and I used
4.1 to create the same type of plan.
Now, it created a good plan, but look, I
think this is where it really gets
interesting because what I did is I went
ahead and asked Chachi5 Pro to compare
the plan it made to my second plan that
I took from Claude. Can you compare it
to the alternative plan that I have,
which one is better and what are the
differences? Kind of purposefully
leaving a bit of ambiguity around which
one is better. Then I pasted Claude's
entire plan which is right here. Again,
you can kind of pause and look at this
if you want some of the details. And
here's the difference between the two
plans. GPT5 met me where I'm at right
now with the app. It gave me a plan
that, you know, with developers would be
executable with a small team, which is
in a few weeks or months. Whereas Claude
gave me a plan that I would need 6 to 12
months for. And it completely refought
the entire application. It figured that
hey, I will want third-party modules,
different model packs depending on the
user, cross module workflows, an entire
marketplace. It basically thought of it
as a startup and how it could take it
all the way to production, which is not
a bad thing in general, but it's a
terrible thing for me because I'm just
trying to make this application work a
little better rather than thinking of a
project that I would execute with 10
developers. It's kind of sweet that GPT5
Pro also gave me a plan that kind of
mixes those two approaches. But
ultimately what I was really looking for
without even specifying it was this
near-term plan to just harden the app,
make it better, make things that are
there right now work properly so I can
move on to the next phase rather than
thinking of the big picture which might
be like a one to two-year vision for
this thing. And I say that because if I
took the plan from Claude and I gave it
to Claude codes to actually execute on,
it would never be able to implement that
gigantic vision. Whereas right now, I'm
working through this plan step by step
with clawed code to actually implement
it. Look, I have it on my second screen.
I'm working through this plan step by
step. I'll leave a comment below on how
that went and if it actually fully
worked. Again, I've been struggling to
resolve these issues with other models,
but I think this is a really good
illustration of how these models operate
and what I noticed in GP5 so far. It's
really good at inferring the
instructions that you did not give to it
and it's really good at adhering to the
parts that you did tell it. It respects
every part of your prompt. It respects
every part of your request and executes
on it at a level that I haven't seen
before when it comes to code. So for
development, I'm still using clot code,
but I will absolutely be using GPT5,
especially this pro mode to plan new
phases to review the code that cloud
code creates to create realistic plans.
I mean, I guess ideally I would have
claude code with GPT5, which would be a
different product and no, the OpenAI CLI
doesn't work as well. Point being, it's
insane at development. And to really
drive that point home, one more quick
example that actually Sam Alman tweeted.
It's to build a little beatbot. And I
also learned something while testing
this in both GPT and Claude. So, first
of all, if you go to the pro mode, you
cannot create this interactive apps
right in here. When I prompt this in the
pro mode, it did everything. Even
created the song for me that I can
download, but it does not have this
ability to create a little interface.
So, that's just something to consider.
And now let's have a practical look and
compare it to the same prompt inside of
Claude.
Okay, so I suppose I could shift things
here, huh? And add a little note.
Okay, that's kind of sick.
Nice. I like the snare drum there. So,
this works super well. Beautiful little
interface. Now, let's do the same thing
inside of Claude here. They've been the
best at these little interfaces, no
doubt. And even this publish button is
something that OpenAI doesn't have yet.
But let's get to the app now.
Okay, let's add a triple snare here.
Okay, so I like the way this is
self-contained and it doesn't go off
screen. So I'll give that to the
artifact. But then also I kind of prefer
the simplistic interface here. No, this
is more colorful. Both work equally as
well. Ah, there's even presets here. So
there's a techno preset.
trapped preset.
To be fair, I didn't ask for that.
Usually Claude is ambitious like that
and just creates these master plans that
it tries to execute on. So, I think that
just reflects the first point that I
made really well. But yeah, both of them
did really well. I mean, if I had to
pick one based on this prompt, I mean,
with the ability to add new instruments
here and the music sounding better, I
got to give it to GBT5. Interesting. So,
let's round out this segment for now.
Obviously, I'll be following up in the
coming days and weeks with more videos,
more comparisons, but as of right now,
when it comes to these five use case
categories, what would I be using for
writing? I really like GBT5. I think it
sounds great. I haven't fully made up my
mind it if I like Opus better, but I
just use GPT all the time and it's right
there. So, I think for writing, it's
going to be GBT5. For business use
cases, 03 was actually my go-to. Now,
with GPT5 being similar to 03 and this
ability to do GPT5 Pro in here, from
what I've tested so far, I don't see
this changing for business, marketing,
sales use cases. GPT5 still, it's a
slightly better free and I love that.
So, there you go. So, I'm going to be
using that. For development, it's going
to be a mix. I'm going to stick with
Claude Code because just nothing matches
its agentic ability to multi- aent
orchestration, tool use. I'm sure
there's going to be more competitor
products in the future, but as of right
now, it is cloud code. But as I showed
and discussed here, I'm starting to kind
of wish I had GPT5 inside of Claude Cod.
And I think that's why a lot of people
are raving about GPT5 within Kurser and
saying it's next level. Look, that's the
top comment on yesterday's video, for
example, with many more reflecting that
sentiment all across the internet. So
really, it's going to be a mix of GPT5
and Opus 4.1 in cloth code. From
research, from what I've seen so far, I
think still Gemini's deep research is
the best product on the market right
now. And for coaching and psychological
use cases, this thing is super
empathetic, as I pointed out in
yesterday's video. And this is the one
where I don't feel fully confident in
making a recommendation just yet, but I
like the tone of it. I think most people
are going to enjoy it, just like they
enjoyed GPD40. And from what I've seen
so far, its ability to really meet you
where you're at right now, having an
understanding for your situation, and
inferring some of the parts of the
prompts that you might not have
specified, I'm heavily leaning toward
GP5. the other competitors on coaching
or psychological use cases. So that's my
GBD5 verdict for now. Now let's look at
some other pieces of AI news that you
can use because there's a lot this week.
Okay, so next up we're going to talk
about a term that was brand new to me
and that's because it's something that
hasn't existed until recently. So you've
probably heard of an IDE, an integrated
development environment. That's what
developers use to edit their code. But
have you heard about an ADE? It's a new
term that is going around for software
that isn't just designed for humans, but
it keeps agents in mind every step of
the way. So instead of an IDE, we're
talking about an AD here, an agentic
development environment. And one of the
biggest companies in the space right now
is Warp, the sponsor of today's video.
Warp is a top coding agent with really
impressive benchmark results on the ones
that matter. top five on Swebench
verified and number one on terminal
bench which even beats out some of the
big players like Clot Code and Gemini
CLI. So the unique thing here is that
Warp lets you develop with multiple
agents and in that sense it's a lot like
Claude Code but with way more
userfriendly UX and code editing
capabilities because it's a standalone
app rather than being locked into your
terminal. So it's not an IDE with
integrated AI like cursor and it's not a
command line interface like clot code.
It's a true ad combining these two
models into one and it's built from the
ground up with agents and humans in
mind. So let me tell you over the past
few months I've been using claude code a
lot but not just that warp is more
beginner friendly but it also brings
several things to the table that claude
code doesn't. Most significantly you can
pick from various models. So if
enthropic might be having an outage you
can use other models or you can use
something like Gemini 2.5 Pro for its
strengths in reviewing code. The entire
visual interface is way richer because
it's a native standalone application and
it's built for this multi-step workflows
where you build, test, refactor, push to
get, do it again. Want to check out what
this whole AD thing is about for
yourself? For a limited time, our
friends over at Warp are giving away the
premium pro plan for only $5 for the
first month. If you want to check it
out, go to the link at the top of the
description and use the code advantage
to redeem that offer and get started
with Warp today. And now, let's look at
the next piece of Aanos that you can
use. So the next story here are
open-source models from OpenAI that came
out earlier this week. If you missed
this, this is actually a big deal. And
this one is kind of getting buried under
all the other significant stories this
week, but it actually matters because
yes, we've seen a lot of open- source
openweight models that you can download,
run locally, and use fully privately,
fully offline. We've seen this. I've
done tutorials on how to use them on
this channel. There's a plethora of them
with new ones coming out every week. But
these are different because they passed
the vibe check, they passed the smell
test, whatever you want to call it.
People are absolutely in love with these
models. The sentiment across the
internet is extremely positive towards
them. And rather than just going ahead
and running a few test prompts in here,
which you know I can do and you can do
and we could spend a few minutes looking
at some results here. These models don't
do anything groundbreaking, but they do
many things better than all of the
competition. namely, they're as
efficient as ever, with one of them
being 20 billion parameters and the
second 120B parameters. But only a
fraction of those are active parameters,
which means that the small model even
runs on some phones. And again, rather
than just spending a few minutes
prompting random stuff here and being
like, "Yeah, they're all right." The
bigger one is almost atree level when
you look at the benchmarks, which is
seriously impressive cuz almost leading
the pack in some of these benchmarks.
And anecdotally, I'm a friend of mine
and a friend of the channel, Mark, that
has been helping accountants build their
businesses for most of his life now,
actually was struggling with one
question recently, and that is how to
use a local model to actually perform
data analysis and work with numbers
reliably. I was talking to him and he
told me that he tried all these models
out there with the common recommendation
being the GMA models, but they just did
not work reliably enough. And guess
what? this week when he tried the same
use case he's been looking for ever
since the release of chat GPT and now
that he's using the smaller model here
the 20B he managed to get reliable
mathematical results out of the models
actually calculating revenue correctly
based on large tables now this even
surprised me but when you look at the
benchmarks like this thing has almost
perfect scores on competition math and
if you crank up the reasoning it has a
chance to selfcorrect and all of a
sudden these models can do mathematics
whereas none of the other open source
models he was trying and he said tried
almost all of them have been able to do
this reliably. So I just kind of wanted
to leave that little story here for you
to consider and generally the sentiment
around these just has been that yeah
these are the best open source models
out there that you want to be using if
you get the choice. So if you're going
to be building something definitely
consider these. Okay, let's see what's
next which would be Grock Imagine. This
is a image and video generator by Grock
and we did thorough testing on this and
let me just show you the results of this
testing without wasting too much of your
valuable time. So let's start with image
testing. So as you know we put together
this sheet and publish a monthly ranking
on the best image generators over in the
free area of our community. As a part of
this sheet we now also have Grock
imagine and you can see that on logo
design. This doesn't even come close to
some of the other models here. I think
these are some of the most recent and
significant ones. If you want to compare
it with Flux, you can just scroll to the
right here. I'll leave a link below.
Point being, yeah, at that it's pretty
bad. Portrait photography, super blurry,
not even close to realistic. The
cinematic still actually looks really
good. That's the one where I would say,
okay, good job, Grock. It does text
well, as do all the other top models
now. And the comic is okay. I don't
know. I'd say just another pretty good
image generator. Nothing that blows me
away, but that is kind of hard at this
point. So, let's have a look at some of
these video clips on some of these
benchmarking prompts that we run on
every single video generator that comes
out. Then, we also publish a monthly
rating just as we do for LLM platforms
like Chat GBT2. You should check those
out, but for now, we're looking at these
videos. Actually, super realistic. Now,
the weird thing is they do include
sound, but the sound is just kind of
trash.
[Music]
Let's be real. I mean, they just added
some random sound effect. This has
nothing to do with the quality of V3.
Car looks good. I always look at these
wheels. They kind of show you the
quality of the generator immediately.
And even this robot looks good. I'm
usually most critical of this shot cuz
it shows both water and human anatomy.
Both of those did okay on here. And
that's kind of the story of this entire
video and image generator. It's okay.
It's good. It can keep up with some of
the better models, but it's definitely
not surpassing any of them. And that is
sort of it for Grock Imagine. Nothing
crazy, but okay. They're in the game
now, too. Whereas the next story is way
more interesting in my opinion. When I
saw this, I immediately wanted to try
this and now I finally have the chance.
So, I signed up for a premium account to
runway alf. And this is essentially
Photoshop for video. Doing the stuff
that this can do with some text prompts
is extremely tricky with visual effects.
So, let's not waste any more time. Let
me just select ALF here and do something
like add rain to the scene. And I just
took some random video of me presenting
something here in the studio. We'll add
rain to the scene. And then we'll do one
more. Set the microphone
on fire and generate that. What I'm
going to be looking out for is the
physics of the rain. Is it going to pick
up on the fact that there's like a floor
in the background? Is it going to be
bouncing off my chair? I'm really
curious to see this. The demo video of
this looks super impressive. Have you
seen this? Like seriously, you can do
different angles. It's kind of crazy.
Attach the camera to the suitcase.
That's great. You can change the
lighting. Oh, I love this art style
actually. So, let's see for ourselves.
Okay, they're done generating. Let's
have a look. Oh, so it just added a
window with rain. That's not bad. It
actually looks like a window with rain.
Maybe my set should have a window with
rain. I kind of like the idea. It's not
exactly what I expected from it here,
but then I wasn't too precise with the
prompt. I just said add rain. Not that
it should add rain anywhere. And this
one set the mic on fire. Look at that.
Look at what it does to my face. There's
reflections. I mean, there's a bit of
morphing, but this is actually pretty
damn good. Wait, let's do one more.
Okay, I'll say add heavy rain to the
entire scene. Let's go. Oo, here comes
the heavy rain. That does look heavy.
Whoa. Yeah, I mean it's heavy rain.
>> I am under the water. Please help me.
>> Fair enough. I like that it kind of like
mirrors my body and reflects off of it.
Interesting. I mean, this is certainly
not bad. Like this fire effect. You can
really see the microphone melting here.
It's not perfect, but I don't think it
needs to be. It's visual effects for
next to no money. That's kind of it. And
except for the waiting time, it's almost
instant and it's super low effort. going
to think about creative ways of using
this in coming videos. Let's see what's
next. So, for the next story, I want to
show you a category that we haven't been
looking at at all over the past few
months, and that's AI music generation.
And before you skip to the next story
because you feel like all the music
generators kind of don't have a used to,
hear me out, or more like hear the new
11 Labs music generation model out
because this thing is well, I'll just
say it head and shoulders above anything
that we've heard so far. The clarity of
the voices, it's kind of unmatchable.
[Music]
>> So, let's just quickly generate
something here and have a listen
together. Cinematic orchestral epic
vocal opening scene with choir and
female solo. What I'm looking for here
is the vocals because let's be real,
soundwise, a lot of these other music
generators were kind of almost flawless,
I would say. But the vocals were the
part where you could really tell.
All the door
singing
noise from silence
away.
[Music]
>> Okay, sounded great. Maybe one more.
Amy Whouse style female singer on a
Gunkk style beat. Oo, that's a
combination I've always wanted to listen
to. Okay, they needed to change the
prompt a little bit. Fair enough. Cannot
use popular celebrities as I would
expect. Now, let's have a listen to
this.
[Music]
Ooh, funky.
I like this.
Night falls on the city lights in my
eyes. Cruising through memories every
turn.
That just sounds good.
Chasing shadows where you meet every
[Music]
moment and feels the same.
If it ever feels the same. Yeah.
Hold me in the warmth of your midnight
blow. Let that soulful river take me
where I need to go. Keeping this groove.
I'll find the truth untold. In your arms
I'm anchored, never letting go.
>> I mean, let's be real. You hear this on
the radio, you're not thinking, "Ooh,
that must be AI." No way. It just sounds
so good.
[Music]
>> This is great.
>> Come on. So, look, I'm no music expert,
but god damn, have I tried all of these
generators. And yep, this one to me
sounds like the best available today.
Let's see what's next. So, next up, we
have a cute little app from Google. And
this is something we haven't seen
before. And while not revolutionary, I
did want to show you. It's called Gemini
story books. And we did some testing
here. So you can see some of the inputs
that we did here. Very simple. Create a
story book about why Pluto is no longer
considered a planet. And then the reason
I say we haven't seen this before
because sure AI generates a whole bunch
of things but have you really seen text
to story book yet in this format where
it generates the full book with
illustrations cover everything sort of
ready to be printed? I know I haven't
and I wanted to show you because this
little story about Pluto is actually
great as you would expect it to be. But
the illustrations are even better.
They're what really set this apart. And
honestly just reading through this
little book right here I kind of enjoyed
it. And you can make this too inside of
Gemini. So Google has been really going
strong with all of these experimental
implementations. Last week Google Opal
now this story book notebook elem also
recently got the video overviews just
features we haven't seen out of any of
the competition and I always just love
to see and share that back with you. So
yeah, if you want to create little story
books yourself, you can do that in
Gemini. Now and talking about Google
innovations, well let me just add on
this story. This does not really fit the
show, but I do need to talk about it
because we usually only speak about news
that you can use, applications that are
available today and practical use cases
that you could consider for yourself. In
this case, we're talking about Genie
Free, which is not available today, but
this is a brand new category of AI
product. And not just a little story
book generator, but this is a text to
world generator, literally. And these
worlds are interactive. So, you might
have seen the previous versions of this
like Genie 2. They got a lot of
attention already, but this is on a
whole new level. So, it generates these
interactive worlds that you can then
navigate with arrow buttons and it
essentially operates like a computer
game, but all of it is generated. And
the interesting thing about this, I
really thought about this is this is
technology looking for a use case. We
don't know what this is going to be good
for yet. Sure, if you can do this in
real time, VR headsets are kind of going
to completely pop off because, well, you
would be able to generate worlds on
demand. But as of right now, I can't
really think of a way to kind of
implement this meaningfully into any
workflow that I'm aware of. I mean,
we're really at a phase where the
technology is getting ahead of what
humans can do with it. Even if AI
development stopped right now, we would
have years and years of figuring out all
the different use cases for this tech.
And this one concretely just goes beyond
anything we've seen it. If this
interests you, I would strongly
recommend you check out their blog post.
There's a lot of little videos that will
help you develop a feeling for what even
a AI world generator might look like.
And while you might not be able to use
this today, I think this is going to be
a big product category once people
eventually figure out what problem that
we can't even properly name today this
will eventually solve. I mean, honestly,
between the two of us, this in the not
safe for work category is obviously
going to be huge and probably not so
great for humanity. But then in gaming,
we kind of have better versions of this.
So, I don't really see it catching foot
there. If you have an idea of what this
could be used for, please leave a
comment below. I'd be super curious to
hear kind of your takes on what a world
generator could be used for. And I think
I should add the limitation that I was
just speculating when I said that it
could generate in real time for VR
headsets. Right now, it can't.
Nevertheless, some insane results that
you should totally be aware of. Let's
see what's next. And that is the Opus
4.1 release. I can't believe this is
sort of a side story. this week, but it
is because this is literally my most
used model. Heck, if I look into my
second screen, I have a version of
clawed code running here with multiple
agents working in tandem since I don't
know like half an hour. This is probably
going to run for another 30 minutes
until it completes what I gave to it.
And I am actually using the Opus model
on this and they just upgraded that. So,
it has slightly better results on
software engineering tasks and it's just
a welcome upgrade to anybody who uses
the claw models. probably not a reason
to change just because they upgraded
from 4 to 4.1. But for everybody using
clot code or their web assistant, this
is a very welcome update. I think the
most important sentence in all of this
is this one. We recommend upgrading from
Opus 4 to Opus 4.1 for all uses. So next
time you're building something, make
sure to use the new 4.1 API. And in the
web interface, it's just default. And
they pointed out that especially the
search has been upgraded, which is one
of the biggest parts of cloud code. It
basically looks over your entire
codebase and then creates to-do list and
uses multiple agents to get things done
for you. But all that starts with the
agents actually understanding the
codebase which this should help with.
And as I'm using cloth code on a daily
right now by the way it's absolutely
insane and some of these multi- aent
workflows I'll be teaching in the
community soon and I'll also be creating
YouTube content on it especially on how
to get into it as a beginner even if
you're not a software engineer. I think
there's a lot to be unlocked there. You
can do these multi- aent workflows like
have a researcher, have a writer, have a
reviewer, researcher goes out, finds
data on the web, writer writes something
up, editor comes up with notes and then
the writer rewrites based on those
notes. And all of that can be done in
one prompt and it just like works for
half an hour and the results are better
than anything you will ever achieve from
a single prompt in chat JPT. And that's
a writing use case. Development
obviously is insane and people even use
as a personal assistant. Again, more
content on that both on the YouTube and
especially in the community cuz this is
sort of more intermediate to advanced
stuff. But yeah, Cloud Opus 4.1 is here.
Use it if you've been using Opus 4
before. It already was one of the best
models out there. Now it's even better.
Okay. And for this week's quick hits, we
have a few short but interesting
stories. Starting out with chat shipping
a feature where if you're chatting for
too long, it's actually going to check
in on you and suggest a little break. I
like this direction that they're taking.
I think some people spend too much time
at their computer and I don't think
humans should be chatting with chatbots
all day, although they are super
helpful. Interesting update. Expect a
little nudge in the right direction if
you spend too much time on it. The
second one should not really be a quick
hit. But I'll be honest with you, I just
don't want to upgrade to the Ultra
account again cuz I don't use Gemini
outside of running deep researches here
and there. But they essentially shipped
their flagship model finally, Gemini 2.5
Deep Think, which if you remember from
their keynote was that super impressive
model that they teased at the beginning
of the presentation, but then just said
that it's coming later. Well, later is
now, so it's out. And on competition
math, it gets 99.2% winning the gold
medal in the math Olympics. That's
better than humans perform. It's good on
humanity's last exam, but GPT5 has it
beat now on that and some of the other
benchmarks here. I believe GPT5 is
around 40% on humanity's last exam now
being state-of-the-art. So, this model
is certainly impressive, but honestly,
with all this competition of OPUS and
GPT5, it's just another really
impressive thinking model that most
likely does nothing so well that you
just need to immediately drop the $200
to get access to this. I mean, GBT5 is
accessible for free today. So, I think
that should change up the way these
things are priced, but then OpenAI might
also be shipping more specialized models
in the future that they'll be charging
more for. Who knows, this thing is out.
If you're on the ultra plan, you're
going to want to use this. The next
quick hit is just something I wanted to
show you. So, Kaggle introduced various
game arenas where they let models battle
it out in different games. And they
started with chess and you can just look
at this bracket that it's playing for.
Unfortunately, GBD5 is not on here yet,
but yeah, actually this finished. When I
was looking at our research, this wasn't
done yet, but apparently 03 won 40
against Grock 4. If you want, you can
even look at the replay of the chess
match between the two models. I love
creative evaluations like this.
Minecraft bench chess text input. Great
stuff. Now, I want to see 03 battle
against GPT5. Maybe I'll follow up with
that next week. And that's pretty much
everything we have for this week. Boy,
this has been a bit of an exhausting
one. I hope you found something that
will upgrade your day-to-day workflows.
If you enjoyed this video, don't forget
to leave a like. It really does help the
channel. And with that being said, my
name is Igor and I hope you have a
wonderful week.